In a world gone mad, being insane was just a way to fit in.
Adam Resurrected is a drama, war film directed by Paul Schrader.
After again attempting to commit murder, a Jewish man with a mysterious past and extraordinary intelligence,
charisma, and body control returns to an insane asylum, where he makes a startling discovery.
Adam Stein, played by Jeff Goldblum.
Commandat Klein, played by Willem Dafoe.
Dr. Nathan Gross, played by Derek Jacobi.
Gina Grey, played by Ayelet Zurer.
Rachel Shwester, played by Hana Laslo.
Abe Wolfowitz, played by Joachim Król.
Adam Resurrected (other titles: Hebrew: אדם בן כלב, romanized: Adam Ben Kelev, German: Ein Leben für ein Leben: "Life for Life") is a 2008 drama
film directed by Paul Schrader and written by Noah Stollman, based on the 1969 novel of the same name by Israeli author Yoram Kaniuk.
The Hebrew title literally translates to Adam, Son of a Dog.
The film tells the story of a Jewish man who, before the
Holocaust, was considered Germany's greatest entertainer.
He is forced by a concentration camp commander to live like a
dog and entertain those condemned to death.
After the war, in the early 1960s, he is hospitalized in a psychiatric
institution for Holocaust survivors in the Judean Desert.
The film explores themes of israel, nazi, holocaust
(shoah), campo de concentración.
The tone is emotional.